Hey what's going on guys.
Welcome to your next project.
So this is gonna be a number guessing game but instead of typing in a number we're actually going to
speak it and we're gonna use the speech recognition API.
Now the reason you see this on my screen.
Congrats you've guessed the numbers because as soon as I start talking IT'S GOING TO RECORD.
RECORD MY VOICE I've already clicked a little notification where you can allow it to access your microphone.
OK so basically we can guess a number between 1 and 100.
If it's lower than the number it'll tell us to go higher if we're higher it'll tell us to go lower.
And if it's not a number it'll tell us that it's not a valid number.
It'll also tell us if we're out of range.
So what I'm gonna do is click the play again button and then I'd give you a demo of the app and then
the console you can see the correct number down here.
So let's click Play Again 40
Hello
47.
And there you go.
So we guess the number.
OK.
So that's the project that we'll be building.
And again we'll be using the speech recognition API which still is in experimental mode.
In fact if you're using you want to use Chrome or Firefox and if you're using firefox you may have to
set a flag which I'll show you in the next video and then we'll start on the team Alan CSX and then
we'll move to the javascript.