All right so we're going to start on our speak no guesser app.
Now this speech recognition API that we're using is it's an experimental technology.
So it's not widely supported it's fully supported in Chrome.
If you're on Firefox there is a flag that you'll have to enable.
So I'm just going to show you how to do that real quick.
So I'm just going to open up my Firefox browser and in the bra.
And there you are Albar here.
I'm just going to say about Colon config and then accept the risk and continue it's just it just allows
us to change flags in the browser and we're going to search for a speech recognition or just speech
and let's see.
We want to set this right here.
MEDIA WEB speech recognition force enable you want to set that to true.
You can see mind's already set to true.
Yours will probably be set to false.
So you just want to click this right here and that will toggle from false to true.
So you want to make sure that that and this one here this recognition enable is true as well in order
for this to work and in order to basically be able to use your microphone in the application.
All right.
So let's jump into v as code and as far as my files I just have my main three my index SPY style sheet
my script and then I have two images in the I AMG folder ones the background image and one is the microphone
image to PMG.
OK so let's start off with the H team L which is gonna be really really simple.
So let's generate a boilerplate here and we'll say no or let's say speak no guests.
I mean I could call it something a little better but that's fine whatever.
So let's add in our link to our style sheet style CSX and then let's add in our script source which
is going to be script J.S. and the each team is going to be really simple for us.
We're just going to have our image of the mike which is I am G slash Mike PMG.
I'll just say I don't know speak for the old and then underneath that we're gonna have our H one and
our each one is going to say guess a number between one and one hundred and then we're gonna have an
h three and just say speak number into your microphone.
And then the last thing we're gonna have is just a div with the I.D. of M.S. G for message and a class
of M.S. G.
Now ultimately this is gonna be empty because what is gonna be put in here is going to be generated
into the DOM through javascript it's gonna be like what we say and if we're correct and stuff like that.
So for now I'm just going to hardcoded in so we'll put a div here and it's going to say you said coal
and then underneath that we'll have a span and I'm going to give this a class of box and it's gonna
have the number I'll just put a 20 in here for now and then underneath that it'll say like go lower
go higher or whatever.
So that's gonna be put into a div.
Let's just say go higher.
So that's what it will look like.
So we'll save that and let's open this up in life server K and then I'm just going to make this smaller
that small if I can grab onto it all right.
So we have the H SYMBOL.
Now we're gonna add our style which is pretty simple.
First thing we'll do is just set our box sizing on everything to border box.
And then for the body we'll set our background.
So I'm going to set a color in an image so the color will be hexadecimal to F 3 5 4 2 and then for the
image we're gonna say you are L and it's gonna be in the image folder and then be g dot J Peg let's
set a no repeat and let's set the positioning to left left center and we want to cover.
Okay.
And we wanted to take up the whole thing so let's say Men height on the body will be 100 viewport heights
and we'll add our color of white.
Let's just close that sidebar up and I want everything to be in the middle so I'm going to display flex
and also select set the Flex direction to column K and then to align everything to the middle we'll
do a line item center let's do justify content center and let's do text align center.
OK.
Some puts everything in the middle and then we'll add a margin zero and then just apply a font so let's
use we'll just use aerial here K to make this a little wider.
And if you want to add a media query to make the text smaller on really small screens you can do that
if you want but I've done that in enough projects it's it's pretty simple so I'm not going to bother
doing it here.
Let's let's fix the headings because these are kind of far apart here that the each one in the each
three.
So we'll just take the H one and h three and let's just set a margin bottom to zero looks like I put
two ends in no
OK.
Now there is gonna be part of this that we can't see right now.
Once we guessed the correct number we're gonna replace everything in the body with just a paragraph
that says you've guessed the correct number and it's gonna have a play again button.
So I'm just gonna add some style for the paragraph I'm just gonna change the line height to one point
five spread the line a little bit and then just set the margin to zero and then for the play button
so it'll have a class of play B T N or let's play again.
So this is just gonna have a padding of eight on the top and bottom in 15 on the sides and then I'm
gonna just remove the border set the background set the background to a light grey let's do f for three
times and then just make it rounded radius 5 pixels and just set a margin top to bring it down a little
bit so we'll set that to 10 pixels.
OK now let's work on this this whole part right here which is the message.
So for the message itself I missed G class.
I'm going to set the font size.
We'll do one point five m and m unit is just it's relatable to its parent.
So it's going to be one point five times whatever the parent font is.
And then let's set a margin top to move it down and I'll set that to 40 pixels.
OK now for the box number the number has a box class.
So I want to have like a you know an outline or a border around that.
So let's say border and let's do one pixel solid and the color will be d e three times so really light
gray and I'm going to display it as an inline block because if you recall it's a span which is by default
it's in line.
And I want to be able to add margin padding so I'll set that to inline block.
I'm going to make the font size a little bigger so it's two 30 pixels.
And then let's set the margin to 20 pixels and we'll set the padding to 10 pixels.
OK so now I get that little box around it.
And that should be it for the for the styling.
All right.
So not too bad at all.
So what I want to do next can close these files up at least that we can get rid of the three lines in
here because like I said this is going to get added with the javascript so we can actually get rid of
that now.
OK.
So our UI is all set in the next video.
We're gonna go ahead and start to implement the speech recognition API generate a random number and
all that good stuff.