OK so now going to start to work with the speech recognition API.
So as you could see here in the docs the speech recognition interface of the web speech API is the controller
interface for the recognition service.
This also handles a speech recognition event sent from the recognition service.
So it shows all the different properties and methods and stuff and what we're going to be working with
is the start method.
So this will start the recognition service and listen to any incoming audio.
So it also send a pop up to the browser to ask if you want to get permission to listen to your mike.
And then as far as events we're going to be listened for the results event.
This is fired off when the speech recognition returns a result.
So basically when you talk into the mike this will fire off and we can capture whatever said and then
what else.
We have the end event.
So this will be fired when the speech service has been disconnected.
And that's those are pretty much the main events and methods will be working with.
So let's jump into our JavaScript file here and the first thing I'm going to do is bring in the dorm
elements which in this case is just one we just want the message element.
So it's used document Dodds get element by D and has an I.D. of message.
So this is basically the output of whatever we want to tell the user if they need to go higher or whatever
and I'll also say whatever they speak into the mike.
So we need a random number between 1 and 100.
So let's go ahead and create a variable called random NUM and set that to a function called get random
number and then we're going to create that function down here get random number and to do this we're
going to return let's return and to generate a random decimal we can use math thought random and then
we can just multiply that by one hundred and then we want to round that down.
So let's go ahead and wrap this in our javascript math dot floor method.
Now this will give us zero through ninety nine.
So we want it to be one through 100.
So we're just going to add one on to that.
All right.
And then let's we'll do a console log up here of random num excuse me and then we'll just open up our
console you can see we get forty five to five ninety eight thirty to seventy 71.
So just keep generating a random number when the page loads and let's just keep this here so we can
see what the correct guess is.
So I'll just say it's the same number.
Cole and then we'll just put a you know.
So it just says no and then whatever the correct number is.
Now for the speech recognition we need to initialize a speech recognition object.
Now in some browsers you might need to use the Web Kit speech recognition.
Like I said this is still kind of an experimental technology.
It's actually go right here.
So I'm going to take window dot speech recognition and set that to window dot speech recognition or
in some cases it might be Web Kit speech recognition.
So I'll say window dot web kids speech recognition.
OK.
So whichever one is available to us now we need to initialize a variable with that with that object.
So we're gonna say let's.
Recognition.
So we're creating a new variable and we're going to initialize a new window dot speech recognition.
OK.
So this will give us an object to work with and the first thing we want to do is start.
So it's a start.
Recognition and game.
So the game is going to start as soon as it loads so we'll say recognition dot start.
So I showed you that method in the documentation and I'm gonna save this Hello OK.
So what happened is you can see that you can see the little microphone blink up top.
So it ran or it started.
It captured what I said into the mike and nothing else happens because we we haven't said anything to
happen yet.
So what we need to do now is listen for the result event.
OK.
So let's say speak result and we're going to take that recognition object and add an event listener
and we want to listen for an event called result.
And then once that happens we'll call a function called on speak.
OK.
So let's see this on speak we'll go and create right above the random number let's put a comment here.
Generate and number
so for this let's say capture or use or speak so function on speak.
And that's part of an event listener so we're going to pass in that event parameter and what we want
to do here.
Let's just console log what that event gives us hello.
So this is what it gives me after I start after it starts and we catch our result and then run this
function.
So this this contains a lot of stuff but what we want to target right here is the results.
Can you see inside results.
And it's really important to recognize the the structure of this because this is how we need how we're
gonna get what we actually said.
So in results is an array it's a speech recognition result array there's only one item.
So it's zero and then there's another array inside that called speech recognition alternative.
So that's another array.
And then there's a property called transcript and that's where our text is K or whatever we said in
this case.
Hello.
So to capture that let's go ahead and get rid of this and let's create a variable called message and
let's set that to to our event and then we want the results.
OK.
So we're going here then we want to go to arrays in both at the zero index.
So the first array helps.
And then the next array and then that array has a property called transcript.
OK so that should give us whatever it is we say so let's console log here.
Message Hello and there we go.
So now we can capture what is said into the microphone.
So pretty easy to get that functionality down.
Now one thing you might notice is it didn't prompt me at all to use my microphone and that's because
I've already dealt with this app on this host.
You will get a prompt to two to allow your microphone to basically get the input to your mike.
OK.
So now what we want to do is call two functions here the first one is going to be right message and
what that's going to do is it's going to just write out what we speak and then we also want to do we
want to check the number which is the point of the game and we're going to pass our message into that.
And that's going to check to see if it's a valid number.
Check to see if it's in between this range and check to see if it matches the actual number.
All right.
So I'm going to comment these out right now and save because we're gonna do these in the next video.
OK.
So when next few will create these two functions and we'll go from there.