OK so now that we can grab the input from the microphone and we're putting it into this variable here
next thing we're gonna do is call a function called right message.
So let's create that.
So this is going to basically this is gonna tell.
Well let's just say right.
What user speaks so function right message.
It's going to take in the message and all we're really gonna do here is take the message element in
the DOM.
So message element and we're gonna add some H team L with enraged him out use some back tricks here
and it's gonna we're gonna put in the same stuff that we did manually and the aged him out earlier which
is gonna be a div that says you said colon and then we're gonna have a span and that's going to have
a class of Bach's styling K and then in here we're gonna have the actual message.
So if I save this and I start to talk it's going to capture what I say and put it in there.
All right now that'll just basically put in what we say but we need to check our number.
Right.
We need to validate to make sure it's a number we need to check to see if it's in range and all that
stuff.
So that's going to go in this function here.
So it's a check message against number.
So it's a function check number which we'll take in the message and first thing we'll do is create a
variable called NUM and set that to the message that's passed in but we want to convert it to a number.
OK.
So just adding a plus sign will convert it from a string to a number.
And then the first check I'm going to do is if it's a valid number
so say F now is a few ways to do this what I'm going to do is use the built in Number object in the.
Is Nan method here which stands for is not a number.
So if our number is not a number then let's take the message element and set the inner aged him out.
Now there's two things we could do here we could append it.
So plus equals and then our message which is going to be a div and we'll say that that is not a valid
number.
So we could append it.
And in this case what it's going to do is it'll stay it'll show what we say.
Just like it did here and then also say that is not a valid number and just keep going or we can just
set it to equals where it'll this will replace what we say so it won't actually it won't actually show
here unless it's a valid number and I think that's what I'm going to do.
But if you want to try it the other way after we're done you can go ahead and do that as well.
OK.
So then we just want to return.
So if I save hello that is not a valid number.
OK.
And then it kind of just stops there.
Now if I reload and I see a number 15 then it's going to go ahead and show.
OK.
So that will check for a valid number.
Now let's make sure it's in range
so say if and let's say if the number is greater than 100 or the number is less than 1 then we're going
to take our message elements set the inner H temple to a div that says No must be between 1 and 100
OK.
So let's try that out.
We just want to return from this as well.
so there we go.
And actually this we're gonna spend because we want to keep playing and I'll show you how we'll do that
after basically when it ends after we say something and it ends we want to restart because we want to
be able to keep guessing but we're gonna do that after.
So now we want to check.
No.
So we're going to first check to see if it matches so we'll say if the NUM is equal to the random num
then we won.
So all we're gonna do is just replace the body.
So I'm gonna say document dot body dot in our each team now and set that to some tactics and we'll put
it here in H2
and we'll say congrats you have guessed you've guessed the number.
And then we'll just put a couple line breaks here and then under that let's just say it was.
And then the number.
And then under the H two I'm just gonna have a play again button so I have button.
Give it a class of play again.
And an idea of play again.
And we'll add an event onto this and a little bit.
OK.
So that should happen if we win.
So down here let's do and.
Else if.
And now let's check to see if the number is greater than the random number.
OK.
So if it's greater then we need to send a message that says go lower right.
So we'll say.
Message element in our H team now and we'll set that to a div
and let's say go lower and then else so else then it's gonna be lower.
So we need to say go higher.
So it's a message element time in our AGM now.
And let's set that equal to a div and we'll just say go higher.
All right.
Oh actually one thing we want to append this right here that go lower.
Go higher.
We want to do plus equals here because we just want to a pen because we still want to show up here where
it shows us what we said we still want to show that in addition to the go lower and go higher.
So this will append instead of replace.
So we're going to save this and reload and then I'll I'll speak in number 50.
OK so what it's doing now is it's it's working but it's only letting me guess once.
Right.
Because we start.
So we call start up here.
It listens.
And then when it gets a result it fires on speak and then we call in the on speak we call right masses
in check number and that's the end of the whole thing.
Right.
Well I want to be able to keep playing.
I want to be able to keep saying the number.
Some of the reload and because when we reload the number changes right.
So what we can do is add an event.
So there's a start.
And actually we want to look at the end event because the end event will fire off when it basically
we're done speaking.
So let's go down here and let's say and as AR service.
So when the speech recognition service ends say the event listener and we want to listen for and and
then when that happens I'm just gonna go ahead and in an arrow function I'm going to call recognition
dot start again.
Now I should be able to keep playing so I'm going to save 70
okay.
So when I hit the right number this runs right here it changes the body the enraged him out to display
this.
All right.
So our game is working what we want to do now is just make this play button work because right now it
doesn't do anything.
So let's go down here and let's add an event.
So I'm gonna since this is generated after the DOM is already painted so weird because we're doing it
with our javascript we're going to add the event listener onto a parent.
So I'm going to add it onto the body.
So add add event listener onto the body and it's gonna be a click event and then we'll go ahead and
run a function and we want to make sure that that what we're clicking on is that button.
So I'll just have an if statement and we'll say if e dot target which means whatever the element we're
clicking on.
If that I.D. is equal to play again because that button has an idea of play again then we're just going
to reload the page and restart the game.
So on the window object we have a location object which has a method called reload.
OK.
So we can just call that 40
43 OK so we won.
I'm going to click this.
He is not the final two got to pass in here.
He had to try it again 44
and there we go so it just resets and it's going to tell me that it's not a no hep C not a valid number.
Now in this case the game stops.
So if I say like 15 it's not going to do anything because we've completely replaced it still listening.
You can see the mike up here.
But we've completely replaced the the guess or is it.
So right here it says you said and then the number we replace that with.
This is not a valid number because we didn't pen so it might actually be a good idea edited to add a
plus sign here so that you can keep playing even if it's not a valid number.
So let's try that 15 Hello
25 20 OK.
So yeah that's probably a better idea because it's a little confusing if we just replace the message
element and then we can't we basically can't play anymore.
So I think that that's a you know that's the right way to do it.
All right.
So that's it.
Guys hopefully you learn something from this video and you can use the speech recognition API to kind
of you know build your own stuff using speech recognition.
I think that's going to be something that's going to gain more popularity as time goes on.
You know with all the A.I. stuff and Alexis and Google homes and all that stuff it's just I think it's
it's going to be really popular in the future but that's it that's going to be the last project for
now.
I do plan on adding more in the future but hopefully you've learned a lot from the projects that you've
done in this course already.
And I would highly encourage you to take what you've learned and start to build your own projects and
come up with ideas and even take the projects from this course and modify them make them better add
new functionality because just watching a course or a tutorial and copying the code that helps you learn.
But when you actually dive in and get your hands dirty and you start creating your own projects or adding
functionality that's I think that's you know 50 percent of learning how to code but that's it.
Guys I want to thank you so much for watching and I thank you for taking this course.